<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>Dayda</title>
  <updated>2020-11-12T00:00:00Z</updated>
  <link rel="self" href="http://localhost:4000/atom.xml"/>
  <author><name>Kin Lane</name></author>
  <id>http://localhost:4000/atom.xml</id>
	<entry>
    <title>WISE NEA/COMET DISCOVERY STATISTICS</title>
    <link href="http://apievangelist.com/2020/11/12/wise-neacomet-discovery-statistics.html"/>
    <updated>2020-11-12T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <content><![CDATA[These tables show discovery statistics for NEAs and comets discovered by NASA’s WISE mission - now renamed to NEOWISE. The first small table shows the number of NEAs, PHAs (a sub-group of NEAs), and comets discovered to-date (within a day or two). The second table shows each object discovered, sorted by designation, with selected parameters describing the object’s orbit.

http://neo.jpl.nasa.gov/stats/wise/
]]></content>
    <id>http://apievangelist.com/2020/11/12/wise-neacomet-discovery-statistics.html</id>
  </entry><entry>
    <title>Timeseries of Arctic-Boreal Lake Area Derived from CubeSat Imagery, 2017</title>
    <link href="http://apievangelist.com/2020/11/12/timeseries-of-arctic-boreal-lake-area-derived-from-cubesat-imagery-2017.html"/>
    <updated>2020-11-12T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <content><![CDATA[This dataset provides near-daily lake area timeseries for 85,358 lakes across four study areas in Northern Canada and Alaska, USA, between May 1 and October 1, 2017. These lake area estimates were produced using digital images from newly developed Planet Labs CubeSats, small satellites with a 4-band (blue, green, red, near-infrared) camera payload. In constellation, CubeSats collected imagery at very high spatial (3-5m) and temporal (near-daily) resolution. From the imagery, each lake’s mean, minimum, and maximum areas and seasonal dynamism were derived. The dataset covers four Arctic-Boreal regions: the Yukon Flats Basin (YFB) in eastern interior Alaska, and the Mackenzie River Valley (MRV), Canadian Shield Transect (CST), and Hudson Bay Lowland (HBL) in Canada.
]]></content>
    <id>http://apievangelist.com/2020/11/12/timeseries-of-arctic-boreal-lake-area-derived-from-cubesat-imagery-2017.html</id>
  </entry><entry>
    <title>SxSW 2016 Leads</title>
    <link href="http://apievangelist.com/2020/11/12/sxsw-2016-leads.html"/>
    <updated>2020-11-12T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <content><![CDATA[Companies that visited the NASA boot at the SxSW 2016 conference.
]]></content>
    <id>http://apievangelist.com/2020/11/12/sxsw-2016-leads.html</id>
  </entry><entry>
    <title>Soil Organic Carbon Stock Estimates with Uncertainty across Latin America</title>
    <link href="http://apievangelist.com/2020/11/12/soil-organic-carbon-stock-estimates-with-uncertainty-across-latin-america.html"/>
    <updated>2020-11-12T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <content><![CDATA[This dataset provides 5 x 5 km gridded estimates of soil organic carbon (SOC) across Latin America that were derived from existing point soil characterization data and compiled environmental prediction factors for SOC. This dataset is representative for the period between 1980 to 2000s corresponding with the highest density of observations available in the WoSIS system and the covariates used as prediction factors for soil organic carbon across Latin America. SOC stocks (kg/m2) were estimated for the SOC and bulk density point measurements and a spatially explicit measure of the SOC estimation error was also calculated. A modeling ensemble, using a linear combination of five statistical methods (regression Kriging, random forest, kernel weighted nearest neighbors, partial least squared regression and support vector machines) was applied to the SOC stock data at (1) country-specific and (2) regional scales to develop gridded SOC estimates (kg/m2) for all of Latin America. Uncertainty estimates are provided for the two model predictions based on independent model residuals and their full conditional response to the SOC prediction factors.
]]></content>
    <id>http://apievangelist.com/2020/11/12/soil-organic-carbon-stock-estimates-with-uncertainty-across-latin-america.html</id>
  </entry><entry>
    <title>SAFARI 2000 Modeled Tropospheric Air Mass Trajectories, Dry Season 2000</title>
    <link href="http://apievangelist.com/2020/11/12/safari-2000-modeled-tropospheric-air-mass-trajectories-dry-season-2000.html"/>
    <updated>2020-11-12T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <content><![CDATA[The ETA Forecast Trajectory Model was used to produce forecasts of air-parcel trajectories twice a day at three pressure levels over seven sites in Southern Africa for the period August 14, 2000 to September 23, 2000. These sites are Durban, Middleburg, Pietersburg, and Springbok, South Africa; Maun, Botswana; Mongu, Zambia; and Windhoek, Namibia. The twice daily three-dimensional wind field (at 0000 and 1200 UTC) was used as input to the trajectory model. By integrating the vertical motion of the air parcels over a period of time, the trajectory model was able to forecast the net vertical displacement of air parcels during 12-hour periods. The resulting trajectory plots represent the three-dimensional transport of air in time and can be used to examine what is happening in the low-to-mid troposphere during flight and ground-based observations. These levels are most significant in terms of the thermodynamic structure of the troposphere, especially the stable layers and accumulation of material between and below them, as well containing the major levels of subsidence over the subcontinent. The trajectory model output and  thermodynamic profiles of the troposphere were used to position aircraft for sampling trace gases, aerosols and other species during the SAFARI 2000 field campaign and to predict regions of high aerosol and trace gas concentrations downwind.The model output data are daily forward and backward trajectory plots at 850 hPa, 700 hPa, and 500 hPa pressure levels for each location. The plots are provided as JPEG images with coordinate, date, and time stamps.
]]></content>
    <id>http://apievangelist.com/2020/11/12/safari-2000-modeled-tropospheric-air-mass-trajectories-dry-season-2000.html</id>
  </entry><entry>
    <title>SAFARI 2000 Global Burned Area Map, 1-km, Southern Africa, 2000</title>
    <link href="http://apievangelist.com/2020/11/12/safari-2000-global-burned-area-map-1-km-southern-africa-2000.html"/>
    <updated>2020-11-12T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <content><![CDATA[The Global Burned Area 2000 initiative (GBA2000) was launched by the Global Vegetation Mapping Unit of the Joint Research Centre of the European Commission, in partnership with several other institutions, to develop reliable and quantitative information on the global magnitude and spatial distribution of biomass burning. The objective of GBA2000 was to produce a map of the areas burned globally for the year 2000, using the medium resolution satellite imagery provided by the SPOT-VEGETATION (VGT) system and to derive statistics of area burned per type of vegetation cover. A subset of the global GBA20000 map was prepared for SAFARI 2000 to map the area burned in sub-Saharan Africa during 2000 on a monthly basis using VGT imagery at 1 km spatial resolution. Burned areas were identified with a classification tree, relying only on the near-infrared channel of VGT. The data used in this work are in the S1 daily synthesis format, i.e. the data are radiometrically calibrated, precisely geo-located, and corrected for atmospheric effects.The data are binary image files of area burned, BSQ format in geographic projection.  There is one file for each month of 2000 and one file for all of the year 2000. There is also a comma-delimited ASCII text file that provides geographic coordinates (latitude and longitude) of the center of each pixel indicated as a burned area for all of 2000.
]]></content>
    <id>http://apievangelist.com/2020/11/12/safari-2000-global-burned-area-map-1-km-southern-africa-2000.html</id>
  </entry><entry>
    <title>SAFARI 2000 Daily Rainfall Estimates, 0.1-Deg, Southern Africa, 1993-2001</title>
    <link href="http://apievangelist.com/2020/11/12/safari-2000-daily-rainfall-estimates-0.1-deg-southern-africa-1993-2001.html"/>
    <updated>2020-11-12T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <content><![CDATA[The Microwave InfraRed Algorithm (MIRA) is used to produce an imagery data set of daily mean rain rates at 0.1 degree spatial resolution over southern Africa for the period 1993-2001. MIRA combines passive microwave (PMW) from the Special Sensor Microwave/Imager (SSM/I) on board the DMSP F10 and F14 satellites at a resolution of 0.5 degrees and infrared (IR) data from the Meteosat 4, 5, 6, and 7 satellites in 2-hour slots at a resolution of 5 km. This approach accounts for the limitations of both data types in estimating precipitation. Rainfall estimates are produced at the high spatial and temporal frequency of the IR data using rainfall information from the PMW data. An IR/rain rate relationship, variable in space and time, is derived from coincident observations of IR and PMW rain rate (accumulated over a calibration domain) using the probability matching method. The IR/rain rate relationship is then applied to IR imagery at full temporal resolution. The results presented here are the daily means of those derived rain rates at 0.1 degree spatial resolution.The rainfall data sets are flat binary images with no headers. They are compressed band sequential (bsq) files that contain all of the daily images for the given year. Each image is an array of 401 lines, each with 341 binary floating-point numbers, containing rainfall at 0.1 degree resolution for the area 10 to 50 degrees longitude and 0 to -34 degrees latitude. The number of band sequential images in each annual file and the associated dates can be found in the file MIRA_data_dates.csv.
]]></content>
    <id>http://apievangelist.com/2020/11/12/safari-2000-daily-rainfall-estimates-0.1-deg-southern-africa-1993-2001.html</id>
  </entry><entry>
    <title>S E- GEOD-50881 Study Samples --- Candida albicans response to spaceflight (NASA STS-115)</title>
    <link href="http://apievangelist.com/2020/11/12/s-e-geod-50881-study-samples-candida-albicans-response-to-spaceflight-nasa-sts-115.html"/>
    <updated>2020-11-12T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <content><![CDATA[https://c3.nasa.gov/genelab/accession/GLDS-20/

This study presents the first global transcriptional profiling and phenotypic characterization of the major human opportunistic fungal pathogen, Candida albicans, grown in spaceflight conditions. Microarray analysis revealed that C. albicans subjected to short-term spaceflight culture differentially regulated 454 genes compared to synchronous ground controls, which represented 8.4% of the analyzed ORFs. Spaceflight-cultured C. albicans induced genes involved in cell aggregation (similar to flocculation), which was validated by microscopic and flow cytometry analysis. We also observed enhanced random budding of spaceflight-cultured cells as opposed to more normal bipolar budding patterns for ground samples, in accordance with the gene expression data. Furthermore, genes involved in antifungal agent and stress resistance were differentially regulated in spaceflight, including induction of ABC transporters and members of the major facilitator family, downregulation of ergosterol-encoding genes, and upregulation of genes involved in oxidative stress resistance. Finally, downregulation of genes involved in the actin cytoskeleton was observed. Interestingly, the transcriptional regulator Cap1 and over 30% of the Cap1 regulon was differentially expressed in spaceflight-cultured C. albicans. A potential role for Cap1 in the spaceflight response of C. albicans is suggested, as this regulator is involved in random budding, cell aggregation, actin cytoskeleton, and oxidative stress resistance; all related to observed spaceflight-associated changes of C. albicans. While culture of C. albicans in microgravity potentiates a global change in gene expression that could induce a virulence-related phenotype, no increased virulence in a murine intraperitoneal (i.p.) infection model was observed. This study represents an important basis for the assessment of the risk that commensal flora could play during spaceflight missions. Furthermore, since the low fluid-shear environment of microgravity is relevant to physical forces encountered by pathogens during the infection process, insights gained from this study could identify novel infectious disease mechanisms, with downstream benefits for the general public. Cells were grown for 24 hours on the space shuttle or as ground-based controls, preserved in RNALater, and stored at -80C. Four samples of each flight- and ground-based controls were harvested for microarray analysis. GAP is Group Activation Pack and each GAP contains 8 FPAs. The numbers represent the # assigned to the particular GAP and the number assigned to the specific FPA (1-8) within the indicated GAP. The same hardware is used for the flight samples and the ground samples.
]]></content>
    <id>http://apievangelist.com/2020/11/12/s-e-geod-50881-study-samples-candida-albicans-response-to-spaceflight-nasa-sts-115.html</id>
  </entry><entry>
    <title>RLC Forest Fire Images in Russia, 1998-1999</title>
    <link href="http://apievangelist.com/2020/11/12/rlc-forest-fire-images-in-russia-1998-1999.html"/>
    <updated>2020-11-12T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <content><![CDATA[This data set is made up of images of forest fires in Russia from NOAA’s Operational Significant Event Imagery (OSEI) archive (http://www.osei.noaa.gov) for the 1998 and 1999 seasons. OSEI fire products include multichannel color composite imagery of wildfire and controlled burn events. Products in this event group show fire, smoke, and hotspots (FSMHS) from the fires.
]]></content>
    <id>http://apievangelist.com/2020/11/12/rlc-forest-fire-images-in-russia-1998-1999.html</id>
  </entry><entry>
    <title>Remote Sensing Systems Radiometer Rain Collocations with JPL RapidScat L2B Swath Grid</title>
    <link href="http://apievangelist.com/2020/11/12/remote-sensing-systems-radiometer-rain-collocations-with-jpl-rapidscat-l2b-swath-grid.html"/>
    <updated>2020-11-12T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <content><![CDATA[This dataset contains the multi-sourced microwave radiometer wind speed, rain and cloud liquid water data collocated to RapidScat Level 2B wind vector cell (WVC) locations. The corresponding NASA mission is officially referred to as ISS-RapidScat. This dataset is produced by Remote Sensing Systems (RSS) with direct funding from the JPL RapidScat project. All of the collocated radiometer data is produced by RSS. The co-located radiometer sources include: 1) DMSP SSM/I (F15) and SSMIS (F16/F17), 2) Coriolis WindSat, 3) GCOM-W1 AMSR2 and 4) GPM Core GMI; more details on these radiometer sources and sensors can be extracted by scrolling down to the “Platform/Sensor” section below this description. RapidScat is a Ku-band dual beam circular rotating scatterometer retaining much of the same hardware and functionality of QuikSCAT, with exception of the antenna sub-system and digital interface to the International Space Station (ISS) Columbus module, which is where RapidScat is mounted. Unlike QuikSCAT, ISS-RapidScat is not in sun-synchronous orbit, and flies at roughly half the altitude with a low inclination angle that restricts data coverage to the tropics and mid-latitude regions; the extent of latitudinal coverage stretches from approximately 61 degrees North to 61 degrees South. Furthermore, there is no consistent local time of day retrieval. This dataset is provided in a netCDF-4 file format that follows the netCDF “classic” model and made available via FTP and OPeNDAP. For data access, please click on the “Data Access” tab above.
]]></content>
    <id>http://apievangelist.com/2020/11/12/remote-sensing-systems-radiometer-rain-collocations-with-jpl-rapidscat-l2b-swath-grid.html</id>
  </entry><entry>
    <title>Realized Cost Savings and Avoidance Decisions</title>
    <link href="http://apievangelist.com/2020/11/12/realized-cost-savings-and-avoidance-decisions.html"/>
    <updated>2020-11-12T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <content><![CDATA[The OMB Office of the Chief Information Officer (OFCIO) has a long-standing practice of making information about Federal IT available to the public through various tools and reports to Congress. Consistent with this practice, OMB OFCIO will be making agency cost savings and avoidances data available to the public via http://www.whitehouse.gov/omb/e-gov. This dataset links to NASA’s Realized Cost Savings and Avoidances data in JSON format.
]]></content>
    <id>http://apievangelist.com/2020/11/12/realized-cost-savings-and-avoidance-decisions.html</id>
  </entry><entry>
    <title>RapidScat Level 2B Ocean Wind Vectors in 12.5km Slice Composites Version 1.3</title>
    <link href="http://apievangelist.com/2020/11/12/rapidscat-level-2b-ocean-wind-vectors-in-12.5km-slice-composites-version-1.3.html"/>
    <updated>2020-11-12T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <content><![CDATA[This dataset contains the RapidScat Level 2B 12.5km Version 1.3 science-quality ocean surface wind vectors, which are intended as a replacement and continuation of the Version 1.1 and 1.2 data forward from orbital revolution number 7873, corresponding to 11 February 2016; on 11 Feb 2016, RapidScat entered it’s 3rd low signal to noise ratio (SNR) state and the initial calibration of low SNR 3 was preliminary during the Version 1.2 release. The fundamental difference between Version 1.3 and the previous Version 1.2 datasets is that the L1B sigma-0 has been re-calibrated during the periods of low SNR states 3 and 4 using re-pointed QuikSCAT data.  The Version 1.1 should still be considered valid up to the first rev of version 1.2 (5127), and similarly version 1.2 shall be considered valid up to the first rev of version 1.3 (7873). The Level 2B wind vectors are binned on a 12.5 km Wind Vector Cell (WVC) grid and processed using the Level 2A Sigma-0 dataset. RapidScat is a Ku-band dual beam circular rotating scatterometer retaining much of the same hardware and functionality of QuikSCAT, with exception of the antenna sub-system and digital interface to the International Space Station (ISS) Columbus module, which is where RapidScat is mounted. The NASA mission is officially referred to as ISS-RapidScat. Unlike QuikSCAT, ISS-RapidScat is not in sun-synchronous orbit, and flies at roughly half the altitude with a low inclination angle that restricts data coverage to the tropics and mid-latitude regions; the extent of latitudinal coverage stretches from approximately 61 degrees North to 61 degrees South. Furthermore, there is no consistent local time of day retrieval. This dataset is provided in a netCDF-3 file format that follows the netCDF-4 classic model (i.e., generated by the netCDF-4 API) and made available via FTP and OPeNDAP. For data access, please click on the “Data Access” tab above. It is advised for users to avoid using the “wind_obj” variable in this dataset since it is minimally applicable and meant primarily for quality assurance; for users who wish to access the objective function values for each ambiguity, it is suggested to use only the “ambiguity_obj” variable. The “wind_obj” variable contains DIRTH probabilities (which are derived form the “ambiguity_obj” objective function values) in the range of 0 to 1 indicating the conditional probability that the true direction is within + or - 2.5 degrees of the retrieved wind direction given the observed backscatter measurements in the cell. If you have any questions or concerns, please visit our Forum at https://podaac.jpl.nasa.gov/forum/.
]]></content>
    <id>http://apievangelist.com/2020/11/12/rapidscat-level-2b-ocean-wind-vectors-in-12.5km-slice-composites-version-1.3.html</id>
  </entry><entry>
    <title>RapidScat Level 2B Ocean Wind Vectors in 12.5km Slice Composites Version 1.2</title>
    <link href="http://apievangelist.com/2020/11/12/rapidscat-level-2b-ocean-wind-vectors-in-12.5km-slice-composites-version-1.2.html"/>
    <updated>2020-11-12T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <content><![CDATA[This dataset contains the RapidScat Level 2B 12.5km Version 1.2 science-quality ocean surface wind vectors, which are intended as a replacement and continuation of the Version 1.1 data forward from orbital revolution number 5127, corresponding to 19 August 2015; the overlapping time period starting on 19 August 2015 corresponds to the first time period of the recorded low signal-to-noise ratio (SNR). The Level 2B wind vectors are binned on a 12.5 km Wind Vector Cell (WVC) grid and processed using the Level 2A Sigma-0 dataset. RapidScat is a Ku-band dual beam circular rotating scatterometer retaining much of the same hardware and functionality of QuikSCAT, with exception of the antenna sub-system and digital interface to the International Space Station (ISS) Columbus module, which is where RapidScat is mounted. The NASA mission is officially referred to as ISS-RapidScat. Unlike QuikSCAT, ISS-RapidScat is not in sun-synchronous orbit, and flies at roughly half the altitude with a low inclination angle that restricts data coverage to the tropics and mid-latitude regions; the extent of latitudinal coverage stretches from approximately 61 degrees North to 61 degrees South. Furthermore, there is no consistent local time of day retrieval. This dataset is provided in a netCDF-3 file format that follows the netCDF-4 classic model (i.e., generated by the netCDF-4 API) and made available via FTP and OPeNDAP. For data access, please click on the “Data Access” tab above. This Version 1.2 dataset differs from the previous Version 1.1 dataset as follows: 1) L1B sigma-0 has been re-calibrated during the periods of low signal-to-noise ratio (SNR) and 2) during low SNR periods the L1B sigma-0 calibration is determined using re-pointed L1B QuikSCAT data. It is advised for users to avoid using the “wind_obj” variable in this dataset since it is minimally applicable and meant primarily for quality assurance; for users who wish to access the objective function values for each ambiguity, it is suggested to use only the “ambiguity_obj” variable. The “wind_obj” variable contains DIRTH probabilities (which are derived form the “ambiguity_obj” objective function values) in the range of 0 to 1 indicating the conditional probability that the true direction is within + or - 2.5 degrees of the retrieved wind direction given the observed backscatter measurements in the cell. If you have any questions or concerns, please visit our Forum at https://podaac.jpl.nasa.gov/forum/.
]]></content>
    <id>http://apievangelist.com/2020/11/12/rapidscat-level-2b-ocean-wind-vectors-in-12.5km-slice-composites-version-1.2.html</id>
  </entry><entry>
    <title>RapidScat Level 2B Ocean Wind Vectors in 12.5km Slice Composites Version 1.1</title>
    <link href="http://apievangelist.com/2020/11/12/rapidscat-level-2b-ocean-wind-vectors-in-12.5km-slice-composites-version-1.1.html"/>
    <updated>2020-11-12T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <content><![CDATA[This dataset contains the RapidScat Level 2B 12.5km Version 1.1 science-quality ocean surface wind vectors. The Level 2B wind vectors are binned on a 12.5 km Wind Vector Cell (WVC) grid and processed using the Level 2A Sigma-0 dataset. RapidScat is a Ku-band dual beam circular rotating scatterometer retaining much of the same hardware and functionality of QuikSCAT, with exception of the antenna sub-system and digital interface to the International Space Station (ISS) Columbus module, which is where RapidScat is mounted. The NASA mission is officially referred to as ISS-RapidScat. Unlike QuikSCAT, ISS-RapidScat is not in sun-synchronous orbit, and flies at roughly half the altitude with a low inclination angle that restricts data coverage to the tropics and mid-latitude regions; the extent of latitudinal coverage stretches from approximately 61 degrees North to 61 degrees South. Furthermore, there is no consistent local time of day retrieval. This dataset is provided in a netCDF-3 file format that follows the netCDF-4 classic model (i.e., generated by the netCDF-4 API) and made available via FTP and OPeNDAP. For data access, please click on the “Data Access” tab above. This Version 1.1 dataset differs from the previous Version 1 dataset as follows: 1) A new neural network approach for high wind speeds provided rain corrections for the “retrieve_wind_speed” variable for wind speeds in excess of 15 m/s. 2) The data variables containing the number of measurements of each type for each wind vector cell have been corrected; these variables include “number_in_aft”, “number_in_fore”, “number_out_aft”, and “number_out_fore”. 3) The “wind_obj” data variable has been corrected to include the proper data for the conditional probability for the objective DIRTH function values. It is advised for users to avoid using the “wind_obj” variable in this dataset since it is minimally applicable and meant primarily for quality assurance; for users who wish to access the objective function values for each ambiguity, it is suggested to use only the “ambiguity_obj” variable. The “wind_obj” variable contains DIRTH probabilities (which are derived form the “ambiguity_obj” objective function values) in the range of 0 to 1 indicating the conditional probability that the true direction is within + or - 2.5 degrees of the retrieved wind direction given the observed backscatter measurements in the cell. If you have any questions, please contact podaac@podaac.jpl.nasa.gov
]]></content>
    <id>http://apievangelist.com/2020/11/12/rapidscat-level-2b-ocean-wind-vectors-in-12.5km-slice-composites-version-1.1.html</id>
  </entry><entry>
    <title>RapidScat Level 2B Climate Ocean Wind Vectors in 12.5km Footprints</title>
    <link href="http://apievangelist.com/2020/11/12/rapidscat-level-2b-climate-ocean-wind-vectors-in-12.5km-footprints.html"/>
    <updated>2020-11-12T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <content><![CDATA[This dataset contains the RapidScat Level 2B 12.5km Version 1.0 Climate quality ocean surface wind vectors. The Level 2B wind vectors are binned on a 12.5 km Wind Vector Cell (WVC) grid and processed using the using the “full aperture” normalized radar cross-section (NRCS, a.k.a. Sigma-0) from the L1B dataset. RapidScat is a Ku-band dual beam circular rotating scatterometer retaining much of the same hardware and functionality of QuikSCAT, with exception of the antenna sub-system and digital interface to the International Space Station (ISS) Columbus module, which is where RapidScat is mounted. The NASA mission is officially referred to as ISS-RapidScat. Unlike QuikSCAT, ISS-RapidScat is not in sun-synchronous orbit, and flies at roughly half the altitude with a low inclination angle that restricts data coverage to the tropics and mid-latitude regions; the extent of latitudinal coverage stretches from approximately 61 degrees North to 61 degrees South. Furthermore, there is no consistent local time of day retrieval. This dataset is provided in a netCDF-3 file format that follows the netCDF-4 classic model (i.e., generated by the netCDF-4 API) and made available via PO.DAAC Drive and OPeNDAP. For data access, please click on the “Data Access” tab above. This climate quality data set differs from the nominal “slice” L2B dataset as follows: 1) it uses full antenna footprint measurements (~20-km) without subdividing by range (~7-km) and 2) the absolute calibration has been modified for the two different low signal-to-noise ratio (SNR) mode data sets: LowSNR1 14 August 2015 to 18 September 2015; LowSNR2 6 October 2015 to 7 February 2016. The above enhancements allow this dataset to provide consistent calibration across all SNR states. Low SNR periods and other key quality control (QC) issues are tracked and kept up-to-date in PO.DAAC Drive at https://podaac-tools.jpl.nasa.gov/drive/files/allData/rapidscat/ancillary/revtime.csv. If you have any questions, please visit our user forums: https://podaac.jpl.nasa.gov/forum/.
]]></content>
    <id>http://apievangelist.com/2020/11/12/rapidscat-level-2b-climate-ocean-wind-vectors-in-12.5km-footprints.html</id>
  </entry><entry>
    <title>RapidScat Level 2B Climate Ocean Wind Vectors in 12.5km Footprints Version 2.0</title>
    <link href="http://apievangelist.com/2020/11/12/rapidscat-level-2b-climate-ocean-wind-vectors-in-12.5km-footprints-version-2.0.html"/>
    <updated>2020-11-12T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <content><![CDATA[This dataset contains the RapidScat Level 2B 12.5km Version 2.0 Climate quality ocean surface wind vectors. The Level 2B wind vectors are binned on a 12.5 km Wind Vector Cell (WVC) grid and processed using the using the “full aperture” normalized radar cross-section (NRCS, a.k.a. Sigma-0) from the L1B dataset. RapidScat is a Ku-band dual beam circular rotating scatterometer retaining much of the same hardware and functionality of QuikSCAT, with exception of the antenna sub-system and digital interface to the International Space Station (ISS) Columbus module, which is where RapidScat is mounted. The NASA mission is officially referred to as ISS-RapidScat. Unlike QuikSCAT, ISS-RapidScat is not in sun-synchronous orbit, and flies at roughly half the altitude with a low inclination angle that restricts data coverage to the tropics and mid-latitude regions; the extent of latitudinal coverage stretches from approximately 61 degrees North to 61 degrees South. Furthermore, there is no consistent local time of day retrieval. The new version has two important improvements over the previous version 1.0. First, an SST-dependent GMF developed by Lucrezia Ricciardulli of Remote Sensing Systems is used in wind retrieval in order to fix persistent speed biases in Ku-band data over cold ocean.  Second, flagging is simplified and extra flags are provided. All the previously existing flags are still there and still reflect the same meaning and purpose. A new single bit wind_retrieval_likely_corrupted_flag specifies the approximately 3% of the data which is known to have suboptimal performance due to rain, ice, or a few other rare anomalous cases. Another bit wind_retrieval_possibly_corrupted_flag specifies the approximately 15% of the data near rain, near ice, or near the coast, that is thought to be high quality but may not match up well with numerical wind models due to either remaining rain/ice/land contamination or variability in the winds near ice, rain, and coasts that are not reflected in the NWPs.  In addition to these two new bits, copious quality information is provided in the data to allow users to tailor flags to meet their own needs. There is also an added a global attribute called rev_status that specifies whether the RapidScat Instrument was in the original (highest data quality) high SNR mode, or one of the four low SNR time periods, the latter of which indicates the accuracy of winds below 5 m/s is degraded. This attribute also serves to identify MARGINAL orbits in which there are large gaps in the data record due to suboptimal spacecraft attitude. Other than gaps in the data, the accuracy of the winds in the MARGINAL orbits are similar to other orbits. This dataset is provided in netCDF-4 format and made available via FTP and OPeNDAP. For data access, please click on the “Data Access” tab above.
]]></content>
    <id>http://apievangelist.com/2020/11/12/rapidscat-level-2b-climate-ocean-wind-vectors-in-12.5km-footprints-version-2.0.html</id>
  </entry><entry>
    <title>RapidScat Level 2A Surface Flagged Sigma-0 and Attenuations in 25Km Swath Grid Version 1.3</title>
    <link href="http://apievangelist.com/2020/11/12/rapidscat-level-2a-surface-flagged-sigma-0-and-attenuations-in-25km-swath-grid-version-1.3.html"/>
    <updated>2020-11-12T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <content><![CDATA[This dataset contains the Version 1.3 ISS-RapidScat Level 2A 25km science data record, which provides surface-flagged sigma-0 in 25km Wind Vector Cells processed using the pulse “egg” Sigma-0 data provided by the Level 1B dataset. Version 1.3 is intended as a replacement and continuation of the Version 1.1 and 1.2 data forward from orbital revolution number 7873, corresponding to 11 February 2016; on 11 Feb 2016, RapidScat entered it’s 3rd low signal to noise ratio (SNR) state and the initial calibration of low SNR 3 was preliminary during the Version 1.2 release. The fundamental difference between Version 1.3 and the previous Version 1.2 datasets is that the L1B sigma-0 has been re-calibrated during the periods of low SNR states 3 and 4 using re-pointed QuikSCAT data. Due to the circular scan of the SeaWinds instrument the expected number of Sigma-0 cells per WVC is not constant. To minimize the L2A data volume, the Sigma-0 cell data are stored as “lists” for each WVC row, with each list indexed by a “cell_index” array to indicate the cross-track WVC membership of the data. Each cell is then checked for land or ice and flagged accordingly. Attenuation corrections for each Sigma-0 measurement are also provided. Data are provided in single-orbit files in HDF-4 format. RapidScat is a Ku-band dual beam circular rotating scatterometer retaining much of the same hardware and functionality of QuikSCAT, with exception of the antenna sub-system and digital interface to the International Space Station (ISS) Columbus module, which is where RapidScat is mounted. The NASA mission is officially referred to as ISS-RapidScat. Unlike QuikSCAT, ISS-RapidScat is not in sun-synchronous orbit, and flies at roughly half the altitude with a low inclination angle that restricts data coverage to the tropics and mid-latitude regions; the extent of latitudinal coverage stretches from approximately 61 degrees North to 61 degrees South. Furthermore, there is no consistent local time of day retrieval. If you have any questions or concerns, please visit our Forum at https://podaac.jpl.nasa.gov/forum/.
]]></content>
    <id>http://apievangelist.com/2020/11/12/rapidscat-level-2a-surface-flagged-sigma-0-and-attenuations-in-25km-swath-grid-version-1.3.html</id>
  </entry><entry>
    <title>RapidScat Level 2A Surface Flagged Sigma-0 and Attenuations in 25Km Swath Grid Version 1.2</title>
    <link href="http://apievangelist.com/2020/11/12/rapidscat-level-2a-surface-flagged-sigma-0-and-attenuations-in-25km-swath-grid-version-1.2.html"/>
    <updated>2020-11-12T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <content><![CDATA[This dataset contains the Version 1.2 ISS-RapidScat Level 2A 25km science data record, which provides surface-flagged sigma-0 in 25km Wind Vector Cells processed using the pulse “egg” Sigma-0 data provided by the Level 1B dataset. Version 1.2 is intended as a replacement and continuation of the Version 1.1 data forward from orbital revolution number 5127, corresponding to 19 August 2015; the overlapping time period starting on 19 August 2015 corresponds to the first time period of the recorded low signal-to-noise ratio (SNR). This Version 1.2 dataset differs from the previous Version 1.1 dataset as follows: 1) L1B sigma-0 has been re-calibrated during the periods of low signal-to-noise ratio (SNR) and 2) during low SNR periods the L1B sigma-0 calibration is determined using re-pointed L1B QuikSCAT data. Due to the circular scan of the SeaWinds instrument the expected number of Sigma-0 cells per WVC is not constant. To minimize the L2A data volume, the Sigma-0 cell data are stored as “lists” for each WVC row, with each list indexed by a “cell_index” array to indicate the cross-track WVC membership of the data. Each cell is then checked for land or ice and flagged accordingly. Attenuation corrections for each Sigma-0 measurement are also provided. Data are provided in single-orbit files in HDF-4 format. RapidScat is a Ku-band dual beam circular rotating scatterometer retaining much of the same hardware and functionality of QuikSCAT, with exception of the antenna sub-system and digital interface to the International Space Station (ISS) Columbus module, which is where RapidScat is mounted. The NASA mission is officially referred to as ISS-RapidScat. Unlike QuikSCAT, ISS-RapidScat is not in sun-synchronous orbit, and flies at roughly half the altitude with a low inclination angle that restricts data coverage to the tropics and mid-latitude regions; the extent of latitudinal coverage stretches from approximately 56 degrees North to 56 degrees South. Furthermore, there is no consistent local time of day retrieval. If you have any questions or concerns, please visit our Forum at https://podaac.jpl.nasa.gov/forum/.
]]></content>
    <id>http://apievangelist.com/2020/11/12/rapidscat-level-2a-surface-flagged-sigma-0-and-attenuations-in-25km-swath-grid-version-1.2.html</id>
  </entry><entry>
    <title>RapidScat Level 2A Surface Flagged Sigma-0 and Attenuations in 25Km Swath Grid Version 1.1</title>
    <link href="http://apievangelist.com/2020/11/12/rapidscat-level-2a-surface-flagged-sigma-0-and-attenuations-in-25km-swath-grid-version-1.1.html"/>
    <updated>2020-11-12T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <content><![CDATA[This dataset contains the ISS-RapidScat on Level 2A 25km science data record, which provides surface-flagged sigma-0 in 25km Wind Vector Cells processed using the pulse “egg” Sigma-0 data provided by the Level 1B dataset. Due to the circular scan of the SeaWinds instrument the expected number of Sigma-0 cells per WVC is not constant. To minimize the L2A data volume, the Sigma-0 cell data are stored as “lists” for each WVC row, with each list indexed by a “cell_index” array to indicate the cross-track WVC membership of the data. Each cell is then checked for land or ice and flagged accordingly. Attenuation corrections for each Sigma-0 measurement are also provided. Data are provided in single-orbit files in HDF-4 format. RapidScat is a Ku-band dual beam circular rotating scatterometer retaining much of the same hardware and functionality of QuikSCAT, with exception of the antenna sub-system and digital interface to the International Space Station (ISS) Columbus module, which is where RapidScat is mounted. The NASA mission is officially referred to as ISS-RapidScat. Unlike QuikSCAT, ISS-RapidScat is not in sun-synchronous orbit, and flies at roughly half the altitude with a low inclination angle that restricts data coverage to the tropics and mid-latitude regions; the extent of latitudinal coverage stretches from approximately 61 degrees North to 61 degrees South. Furthermore, there is no consistent local time of day retrieval.
]]></content>
    <id>http://apievangelist.com/2020/11/12/rapidscat-level-2a-surface-flagged-sigma-0-and-attenuations-in-25km-swath-grid-version-1.1.html</id>
  </entry><entry>
    <title>RapidScat Level 2A Surface Flagged Sigma-0 and Attenuations in 12.5Km Swath Grid Version 1.3</title>
    <link href="http://apievangelist.com/2020/11/12/rapidscat-level-2a-surface-flagged-sigma-0-and-attenuations-in-12.5km-swath-grid-version-1.3.html"/>
    <updated>2020-11-12T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <content><![CDATA[This dataset contains the Version 1.3 ISS-RapidScat on Level 2A 12.5 km science data record, which provides surface-flagged sigma-0 in 12.5 km Wind Vector Cells processed using the pulse “slice” Sigma-0 data provided by the Level 1B dataset. Version 1.3 is intended as a replacement and continuation of the Version 1.1 and Version 1.2 data forward from orbital revolution number 7873, corresponding to 11 February 2016; on 11 Feb 2016, RapidScat entered it’s 3rd low signal to noise ratio (SNR) state and the initial calibration of low SNR 3 was preliminary during the Version 1.2 release. The fundamental difference between Version 1.3 and the previous Version 1.2 datasets is that the L1B sigma-0 has been re-calibrated during the periods of low SNR states 3 and 4 using re-pointed QuikSCAT data. Due to the circular scan of the RapidScat instrument the expected number of Sigma-0 cells per WVC is not constant. To minimize the L2A data volume, the Sigma-0 cell data are stored as “lists” for each WVC row, with each list indexed by a “cell_index” array to indicate the cross-track WVC membership of the data. Each cell is then checked for land or ice and flagged accordingly. Attenuation corrections for each Sigma-0 measurement are also provided. Data are provided in single-orbit files in HDF-4 format. RapidScat is a Ku-band dual beam circular rotating scatterometer retaining much of the same hardware and functionality of QuikSCAT, with exception of the antenna sub-system and digital interface to the International Space Station (ISS) Columbus module, which is where RapidScat is mounted. The NASA mission is officially referred to as ISS-RapidScat. Unlike QuikSCAT, ISS-RapidScat is not in sun-synchronous orbit, and flies at roughly half the altitude with a low inclination angle that restricts data coverage to the tropics and mid-latitude regions; the extent of latitudinal coverage stretches from approximately 61 degrees North to 61 degrees South. Furthermore, there is no consistent local time of day retrieval. If you have any questions or concerns, please visit our Forum at https://podaac.jpl.nasa.gov/forum/.
]]></content>
    <id>http://apievangelist.com/2020/11/12/rapidscat-level-2a-surface-flagged-sigma-0-and-attenuations-in-12.5km-swath-grid-version-1.3.html</id>
  </entry><entry>
    <title>RapidScat Level 2A Surface Flagged Sigma-0 and Attenuations in 12.5Km Swath Grid Version 1.1</title>
    <link href="http://apievangelist.com/2020/11/12/rapidscat-level-2a-surface-flagged-sigma-0-and-attenuations-in-12.5km-swath-grid-version-1.1.html"/>
    <updated>2020-11-12T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <content><![CDATA[This dataset contains the ISS-RapidScat on Level 2A 12.5 km science data record, which provides surface-flagged sigma-0 in 12.5 km Wind Vector Cells processed using the pulse “slice” Sigma-0 data provided by the Level 1B dataset. Due to the circular scan of the RapidScat instrument the expected number of Sigma-0 cells per WVC is not constant. To minimize the L2A data volume, the Sigma-0 cell data are stored as “lists” for each WVC row, with each list indexed by a “cell_index” array to indicate the cross-track WVC membership of the data. Each cell is then checked for land or ice and flagged accordingly. Attenuation corrections for each Sigma-0 measurement are also provided. Data are provided in single-orbit files in HDF-4 format. RapidScat is a Ku-band dual beam circular rotating scatterometer retaining much of the same hardware and functionality of QuikSCAT, with exception of the antenna sub-system and digital interface to the International Space Station (ISS) Columbus module, which is where RapidScat is mounted. The NASA mission is officially referred to as ISS-RapidScat. Unlike QuikSCAT, ISS-RapidScat is not in sun-synchronous orbit, and flies at roughly half the altitude with a low inclination angle that restricts data coverage to the tropics and mid-latitude regions; the extent of latitudinal coverage stretches from approximately 61 degrees North to 61 degrees South. Furthermore, there is no consistent local time of day retrieval.
]]></content>
    <id>http://apievangelist.com/2020/11/12/rapidscat-level-2a-surface-flagged-sigma-0-and-attenuations-in-12.5km-swath-grid-version-1.1.html</id>
  </entry><entry>
    <title>RapidScat Level 1B Time-Ordered Geo-Located Sigma-0 Version 1.3</title>
    <link href="http://apievangelist.com/2020/11/12/rapidscat-level-1b-time-ordered-geo-located-sigma-0-version-1.3.html"/>
    <updated>2020-11-12T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <content><![CDATA[This dataset contains the ISS-RapidScat Version 1.3 Level 1B geo-located Sigma-0 measurements and antenna pulse “egg” and “slice” geometries as derived from ephemeris and the Level 1A dataset. Version 1.3 is intended as a replacement and continuation of the Version 1.2 data forward from orbital revolution number 7873, corresponding to 11 February 2016; on 11 Feb 2016, RapidScat entered it’s 3rd low signal to noise ratio (SNR) state and the initial calibration of low SNR 3 was preliminary during the Version 1.2 release. The fundamental difference between Version 1.3 and the previous Version 1.2 datasets is that the L1B sigma-0 has been re-calibrated during the periods of low SNR states 3 and 4 using re-pointed QuikSCAT data. The pulse “egg” represents the complete footprint of the pulse, which has a spatial geometry of approximately 25 km by 35 km. There are 8 slices that constitute the range-binned components of a pulse each of which has a spatial geometry of approximately 25 km by 7 km. The orientation of the long dimension of the slices varies with the rotation of the antenna and thus does not align with the along/across track orientation of the wind vector grid in the L2B/L2A products. Data are provided in single-orbit files in HDF-4 format. RapidScat is a Ku-band dual beam circular rotating scatterometer retaining much of the same hardware and functionality of QuikSCAT, with exception of the antenna sub-system and digital interface to the ISS Columbus module, which is where RapidScat is mounted. The NASA mission is officially referred to as ISS-RapidScat. Unlike QuikSCAT, ISS-RapidScat is not in sun-synchronous orbit, and flies at roughly half the altitude with a low inclination angle that restricts data coverage to the tropics and mid-latitude regions; the extent of latitudinal coverage stretches from approximately 61 degrees North to 61 degrees South. Furthermore, there is no consistent local time of day retrieval. Caution: this dataset is intended for expert use only. If you must use RapidScat Sigma-0 data but you are unsure about how to use the L1B data record, please consider using either of the following L2A datasets: 1) http://podaac.jpl.nasa.gov/dataset/RSCAT_L2A_12KM_V1.3 or 2) http://podaac.jpl.nasa.gov/dataset/RSCAT_L2A_25KM_V1.3. If you have any questions or concerns, please visit our Forum at https://podaac.jpl.nasa.gov/forum/.
]]></content>
    <id>http://apievangelist.com/2020/11/12/rapidscat-level-1b-time-ordered-geo-located-sigma-0-version-1.3.html</id>
  </entry><entry>
    <title>RapidScat Level 1B Time-Ordered Geo-Located Sigma-0 Version 1.2</title>
    <link href="http://apievangelist.com/2020/11/12/rapidscat-level-1b-time-ordered-geo-located-sigma-0-version-1.2.html"/>
    <updated>2020-11-12T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <content><![CDATA[This dataset contains the ISS-RapidScat Version 1.2 Level 1B geo-located Sigma-0 measurements and antenna pulse “egg” and “slice” geometries as derived from ephemeris and the Level 1A dataset. Version 1.2 is intended as a replacement and continuation of the Version 1.1 data forward from orbital revolution number 5127, corresponding to 19 August 2015; the overlapping time period starting on 19 August 2015 corresponds to the first time period of the recorded low signal-to-noise ratio (SNR). This Version 1.2 dataset differs from the previous Version 1.1 dataset as follows: 1) L1B sigma-0 has been re-calibrated during the periods of low signal-to-noise ratio (SNR) and 2) during low SNR periods the L1B sigma-0 calibration is determined using re-pointed L1B QuikSCAT data. The pulse “egg” represents the complete footprint of the pulse, which has a spatial geometry of approximately 25 km by 35 km. There are 8 slices that constitute the range-binned components of a pulse each of which has a spatial geometry of approximately 25 km by 7 km. The orientation of the long dimension of the slices varies with the rotation of the antenna and thus does not align with the along/across track orientation of the wind vector grid in the L2B/L2A products. Data are provided in single-orbit files in HDF-4 format. RapidScat is a Ku-band dual beam circular rotating scatterometer retaining much of the same hardware and functionality of QuikSCAT, with exception of the antenna sub-system and digital interface to the ISS Columbus module, which is where RapidScat is mounted. The NASA mission is officially referred to as ISS-RapidScat. Unlike QuikSCAT, ISS-RapidScat is not in sun-synchronous orbit, and flies at roughly half the altitude with a low inclination angle that restricts data coverage to the tropics and mid-latitude regions; the extent of latitudinal coverage stretches from approximately 61 degrees North to 61 degrees South. Furthermore, there is no consistent local time of day retrieval. Caution: this dataset is intended for expert use only. If you must use RapidScat Sigma-0 data but you are unsure about how to use the L1B data record, please consider using either of the following L2A datasets: 1) http://podaac.jpl.nasa.gov/dataset/RSCAT_L2A_12KM_V1.2 or 2) http://podaac.jpl.nasa.gov/dataset/RSCAT_L2A_25KM_V1.2. If you have any questions or concerns, please visit our Forum at https://podaac.jpl.nasa.gov/forum/.
]]></content>
    <id>http://apievangelist.com/2020/11/12/rapidscat-level-1b-time-ordered-geo-located-sigma-0-version-1.2.html</id>
  </entry><entry>
    <title>RapidScat Level 1B Time-Ordered Geo-Located Sigma-0 Version 1.1</title>
    <link href="http://apievangelist.com/2020/11/12/rapidscat-level-1b-time-ordered-geo-located-sigma-0-version-1.1.html"/>
    <updated>2020-11-12T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <content><![CDATA[This dataset contains the geo-located Sigma-0 measurements and antenna pulse  “egg” and “slice” geometries as derived from ephemeris and the Level 1A dataset. The pulse “egg” represents the complete footprint of the pulse, which has a spatial geometry of approximately 25 km by 35 km. There are 8 slices that constitute the range-binned components of a pulse each of which has a spatial geometry of approximately 25 km by 7 km. The orientation of the long dimension of the slices varies with the rotation of the antenna and thus does not align with the along/across track orientation of the wind vector grid in the L2B/L2A products. Data are provided in single-orbit files in HDF-4 format. RapidScat is a Ku-band dual beam circular rotating scatterometer retaining much of the same hardware and functionality of QuikSCAT, with exception of the antenna sub-system and digital interface to the International Space Station (ISS) Columbus module, which is where RapidScat is mounted. The NASA mission is officially referred to as ISS-RapidScat. Unlike QuikSCAT, ISS-RapidScat is not in sun-synchronous orbit, and flies at roughly half the altitude with a low inclination angle that restricts data coverage to the tropics and mid-latitude regions; the extent of latitudinal coverage stretches from approximately 61 degrees North to 61 degrees South. Furthermore, there is no consistent local time of day retrieval. Caution: this dataset is intended for expert use only. If you must use RapidScat Sigma-0 data but you are unsure about how to use the L1B data record, please consider using either of the following L2A datasets: 1) http://podaac.jpl.nasa.gov/dataset/RSCAT_L2A_12KM_V1.1 or 2) http://podaac.jpl.nasa.gov/dataset/RSCAT_L2A_25KM_V1.1.
]]></content>
    <id>http://apievangelist.com/2020/11/12/rapidscat-level-1b-time-ordered-geo-located-sigma-0-version-1.1.html</id>
  </entry><entry>
    <title>Outgassing Db</title>
    <link href="http://apievangelist.com/2020/11/12/outgassing-db.html"/>
    <updated>2020-11-12T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <content><![CDATA[This tenth compilation of outgassing data of materials intended for spacecraft use supersedes Reference Publication 1124, Revision 3, September 1993. The data were obtained at the Goddard Space Flight Center (GSFC), utilizing equipment developed at Stanford Research Institute (SRI) under contract to the Jet Propulsion Laboratory (JPL).
]]></content>
    <id>http://apievangelist.com/2020/11/12/outgassing-db.html</id>
  </entry>
</feed>
